SUN/gemini Press Collection 1982-1995
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
SUN/gemini Press Collection 1982-1995
MS 488
SUN/gemini Press Inc.
Includes materials relating to book, chapbook and broadside series published by SUN/gemini Press between 1982 and 1995. Typical files include contract, copyright, correspondence with authors, editors and artists, permissions, final manuscripts, artwork, proofs, layouts, archive copies and flyers. Two publications preserve the complete publication process, including proofs, layouts, multiple manuscripts, and extensive artwork. There are a total of 15 publications represented, including 12 poetry collections, two broadsides, and one catalog.
7 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection
Biographical Note
The SUN/Gemini Press was a not-for-profit corporation founded by Clint Colby in Tucson, Arizona in the 1980s. The press published mainly poets from Arizona and the “desert southwest” and featured cover artwork by artists of the same region. In total, the press published 17 works between 1985 and 2001 including 14 poetry collections, 2 broadsides, and 1 catalog. Authors published include Agha Shahid Ali, Barbara Anderson, Paul Blackburn, Rebecca Byrkit, Meg Davis, Charles Hood, Dorothy R. Lykes, Jane Miller, Sheila Murphy, Kirk Robertson, Richard Shelton, Diane Wakoski, John Francis Warner, Dana Weimer, and Peter Wild.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 2 series.
Series I: Publications 1982-1995
Series I: II. Oversize Materials 1982-1995
Scope and Content Note
Materials relating to book, chapbook or broadside series published by SUN/gemini Press between 1985 and 1995. Typical files include contract, copyright, correspondence with authors, editors and artists, permissions, final manuscripts, artwork, proofs, layouts, archive copies and flyers. The publications by Richard Shelton and Diane Wakoski preserve the complete publication process, including proofs, layouts, multiple manuscripts, and extensive artwork. There are a total of 15 publications represented, including 12 poetry collections, two broadsides, and one catalog. Authors include Agha Shahid Ali, Paul Blackburn, Rebecca Byrkit, Meg Davis, Charles Hood, Dorothy R. Lykes, Jane Miller, Sheila Murphy, Kirk Robertson, Richard Shelton, Diane Wakoski, Dana Weimer, and Peter Wild.
Access Terms
Blackburn, Paul
Shelton, Richard, 1933-
Wakoski, Diane
Wild, Peter, 1940-
Container List
- Series I: Publications, 1982-1995
  This series contains materials associated with 15 publications including 12 poetry collections, two broadsides, and one catalog. Items of interest include materials relating to Diane Wakoski and Robert Shelton because they represent the complete SUN/gemini Press publication workflow.
  - Ali, Agha Shahid – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ali, Agha Shahid – Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ali, Agha Shahid – Final, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ali, Agha Shahid – Manuscripts, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ali, Agha Shahid – Manuscripts – Rejected, circa 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ali, Agha Shahid – Production Materials, 1987; undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Blackburn, Paul – Artwork, Design, and Layout, 1987; undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Blackburn, Paul – Artwork, Design, and Layout, 1987; undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Blackburn, Paul – Correspondence, 1982-1987; undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Blackburn, Paul – Final, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Blackburn, Paul – Manuscripts, circa 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Blackburn, Paul – Manuscripts, circa 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Blackburn, Paul – Production Materials, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Byrkit, Rebecca – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Byrkit, Rebecca – Correspondence, 1993-1995; undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Byrkit, Rebecca – Final, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Byrkit, Rebecca – Manuscripts, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Byrkit, Rebecca – Production Materials, 1995; undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Catalog – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Catalog – Final, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Catalog – Manuscript, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Catalog – Production Materials, 1995; undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Davis, Meg – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Davis, Meg – Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Davis, Meg – Final, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Davis, Meg – Manuscripts, 1994; undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Davis, Meg – Production Materials, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hood, Charles – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hood, Charles – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Rejected Artwork, 1988; 1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hood, Charles – Correspondence, 1987-1991; undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Hood, Charles – Final, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hood, Charles – Manuscripts, 1990; undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hood, Charles – Manuscripts – Digital Copies, 1990; undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hood, Charles – Production Materials, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lykes, Dorothy R. – Artwork, Design, and Layout, 1995; undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lykes, Dorothy R. – Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lykes, Dorothy R. – Final, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lykes, Dorothy R. – Manuscripts, circa 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lykes, Dorothy R. – Production Materials, 1994-1995; undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lykes, Dorothy R. – Reviews, 1995; undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Miller, Jane – “New Body” – Broadside, circa 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Murphy, Sheila – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Murphy, Sheila – Correspondence, 1989-1994; undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Murphy, Sheila – Final, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Murphy, Sheila – Manuscripts, circa 1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Murphy, Sheila – Production Materials, 1993-1994; undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Robertson, Kirk – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Robertson, Kirk – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Robertson, Kirk – Correspondence, 1986-1990; undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Robertson, Kirk – Final, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Robertson, Kirk – Manuscripts, circa 1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Robertson, Kirk – Manuscripts – Removals, circa 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Robertson, Kirk – Production Materials, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Shelton, Richard – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Shelton, Richard – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Binding Proofs, 1986; undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Shelton, Richard – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Cover Jacket Proofs, circa 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Shelton, Richard – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Mock-ups, circa 1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Shelton, Richard – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Mock-ups, circa 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Shelton, Richard – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Offset, circa 1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Shelton, Richard – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Prints, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Shelton, Richard – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Proofs, circa 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Shelton, Richard – Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Shelton, Richard – Final, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Shelton, Richard – Final – Errors, circa 1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Shelton, Richard – Final – Paperbacks, 1986; 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Shelton, Richard – Manuscripts, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Shelton, Richard – Manuscripts – Rejected, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Shelton, Richard – Manuscripts – Setting Manuscript, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Shelton, Richard – Production Materials, 1985-1986; 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Shelton, Richard – Production Materials – Flyers, circa 1986 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Artwork, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Binding Proofs, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Front/Back Matter, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Mock-ups, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Page Proofs, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Page Proofs, 1st, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Proofs, 1st, 1, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Proofs, 1st, 2, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Setting, 1st, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Correspondence, 1984-1986; undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Final, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Manuscripts – Final, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Manuscripts – Other Poems, circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Manuscripts – Rejected, circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Paperback Edition, circa 1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Production Materials, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Wakoski, Diane – Production Materials – Flyer, circa 1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Weimer, Dana – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Weimer, Dana – Correspondence, 1990; 1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Weimer, Dana – Final, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Weimer, Dana – Production Materials, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Wild, Peter – Artwork, Design, and Layout, circa 1994 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Wild, Peter – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Photographs & Negatives, circa 1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Wild, Peter – Artwork, Design, and Layout – Rejected Artwork for Easy Victory, circa 1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Wild, Peter – Correspondence, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Wild, Peter – Final, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Wild, Peter – Manuscripts, circa 1994 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Wild, Peter – Production Materials, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Series II: Oversize Materials 1982-1995
  This series contains final and working broadsides as well as oversize materials relating to the artwork, design, and layout of publications.
  - Oversize Materials (Box 9)